Guide to the Northern Virginia Civil War images collection, 1853-1914
George Mason University Libraries
- Northern Virginia Civil War images collection
  - [Maps II] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 30)
    - No. 11 Map, Showing Routes and Camps of the Army of the Valley Dist. from Staunton, VA., to Washington, D.C., and back to Strasburg, VA., from June 27th to July 22d, 1864, 21.31D; Lithograph; 8 3/4" x 14"
    - No. 99 Wickham's Attack on Fed. Cav., Nov. 22d, 1864, 21.31E; Lithograph; 3" x 2 3/4"
    - No. 8 Map Showing the Routes and Camps of the 2d Corps, A.N.V., from Gaines' Mill to Lynchburg, VA., June 13th to 18th, 1864, and of the Army of the Valley District from Lynchburg to Salem and Staunton, VA., June 19th to 27th, 1864, 21.31F; Lithograph; 5 1/4" x 12 1/2"
    - No. 6 Map, from Maj. A.H. Campbell's Surveys, Showing Position of 2d Corps, A. N. VA., at Hanover Junction, VA. May 22d to May 27th, 1864, 21.31G; Lithograph; 5 3/4" x 8"
    - No. 1 Map, from Maj. A.H. Campbell's Surveys, Showing the Positions of the Camps and Pickets of the 2d Corps, A. N. VA., May 3d, 1864, and the Routes of March from May 4th to May 21st, 1864, to the Battles of the Wilderness and Spotsylvania C. H., VA., 21.32A; Lithograph; 7 1/2" x 11"
    - No. 5 Map, from Maj. A.H. Campbell's Surveys, Showing the Routes and Positions of the 2d Coprs, A. N. VA., from May 21st to May 27th, 1864, 21.32B; Lithograph; 11" x 8"
    - No. 7 Map, from Maj. A.H. Campbell's Surveys, Showing the Routes, Camps,and Positions of the 2d Corps, A. N. VA., from May 27th to June 13th, 1864, 21.32C; Lithograph; 10 1/2" x 8 1/4"
    - No. 11 Map, Showing Routes and Camps of the Army of the Valley Dist. from Staunton, VA., to Washington, D.C., and back to Strasburg, VA., from June 27th to July 22d, 1864, 21.32D; Lithograph; 8 3/4" x 14"
    - No. 99 Wickham's Attack on Fed. Cav., Nov. 22d, 1864, 21.32E; Lithograph; 3" x 2 3/4"
    - No. 8 Map Showing the Routes and Camps of the 2d Corps, A.N.V., from Gaines' Mill to Lynchburg, VA., June 13th to 18th, 1864, and of the Army of the Valley District from Lynchburg to Salem and Staunton, VA., June 19th to 27th, 1864, 21.32F; Lithograph; 5 1/4" x 12 1/2"
    - No. 6 Map, from Maj. A.H. Campbell's Surveys, Showing Position of 2d Corps, A. N. VA., at Hanover Junction, VA. May 22d to May 27th, 1864, 21.32G; Lithograph; 5 3/4" x 8"
    - No. 2 Sketch of the Battle of the Wilderness. Position of 2d Corps. A. N. VA., Thursday, May 5th, 1864, 21.33A; Lithograph; 4 1/4" x 6 1/2"
      Top Eng. 2d Corps
    - No. 3 Sketch of the Battle of the Wilderness. Position of 2d Corps, A. N. VA., Friday, May 6th, 1864, 21.33B; Lithograph; 7 1/4" x 8 1/2"
    - No. 4 Sketch Showing Positions and Entrenchments of the 2d Corps, A. N. VA., During the Battles of Spotsylvania C. H. VA., from May 9th to May 21st, 1864, 21.33C; Lithograph; 6 1/2" x 8"
      Top Engr. V.D.
    - no 14 Map of Action of McCausland's Cavalry Brigade at Hagerstown, Md., Thursday, July 7th, 1864, 21.33D; Lithograph; 6 1/2" x 5 1/2"
      Top Eng. V.D.
    - No. 13 Map of the Capture of North Mountain Depot, VA. by McCausland's Cavalry Brigade, Monday, July 4th, 1864, 21.33E; Lithograph; 6 1/2" x 6 1/4"
    - No. 16 Sketch of the Battle of Rutherford's Farm, VA., July 20th, 1864, 21.33F; Lithograph; 5 1/2" x 6 1/4"
      Top Eng. A.V.D.
    - No. 9 Map of Engagement near lynchburg, VA. Saturday, June 18th, 1864, 21.33G; Lithograph; 9" x 6 1/2"
    - No. 10 Map of Engagement at Hanging Rock, Roanoke County, VA., Tuesday, June 21st, 1864, 21.33H; Lithograph; 10" x 7 1/4"
    - No. 15 Sketch of the Battle of Monocacy, Frederick Co., Md., Saturday, July 9th, 1864, 21.33I; Lithograph; 10" x 7 1/4"
    - Plan of the Battle-Field at Bull Run, July 21st, 1861, 21.34A; Lithograph; 16" x 13 1/2"
      by J. J. Young
    - Map of the Battle-Fields of Manassas and the Surrounding Region, Showing the Various Actions of the 21st July, 1861 between the Armies of the Confederate States and the United States, 21.34B; Lithograph; 16" x 13 1/4"
      by W. G. Atkinson
    - Map of the Rappahannock River from Port Royal to Richards Ferry, 21.35A; Lithograph; 7 1/4" x 19"
      by Brig. Gen. D.P. Woodbury
    - Map of the Field-Operations of the Potomac under Major General Joseph Hooker in the Battles with the Army of General Lee near Chancellorsville and Fredericksburg between April 27th and May 7th 1863, 21.35B; Lithograph; 9" x 16 1/2"
      by Brig. Gen. G.K. Warren
    - Portions of the Middle Department 2nd Division 8th Army Corps, 21.35C; Lithograph; 9" x 10 1/2"
    - Rough Sketch of Reconnaissance May 24th 1862, 21.36A; Lithograph; 4 1/4" x 5"
      Julius Bien and Co.
    - Map Illustrating the Battle of Hanover, VA. May 27, 1862, 21.36B; Lithograph; 4 1/4" x 5"
    - Engagement near Hanover Court-House, VA. May 27 1862, 21.36C; Lithograph; 4 1/4" x 6"
    - Reconnaissance made on the Afternoon of May the 23d 1862, 21.36D; Lithograph; 4 1/4" x 6"
    - Map of March from Mount Airey to Old Church, VA. May 23rd 1862, 21.36E; Lithograph; 4 1/4" x 5"
    - Skirmish between Two Rebel Batteries and Battery B, 1st Md. Art'y June 5th 1862 at New Bridge, VA., 21.36F; Lithograph; 6" x 8"
    - Battle of Mechanicsville, VA. June 26 and 27, 1862 Penn. Reserve-Corps Division Porter's Army Corps, 21.36G; Lithograph; 6" x 5"
    - Sketch of the battle of New market, VA. June 30 1862 Penna. reserve-Corps Division Porter's Army Corps, 21.36H; Lithograph; 6" x 6"
    - Map to Accompany the Report of Brig. Gen. J.E.B. Stuart, C.S. Army Commanding Pamunkey Expedition to the Enemy's Rear June 13, 14 and 15, 1862, 21.36I; Lithograph; 6" x 8"
    - Malvern Hill, VA. Morell's Division July 1st 1862, 21.36J; Lithograph; 6" x 4 1/2"
    - Engagement near Hanover Court-House, VA. May 27 1862, 21.36K; Lithograph; 6" x 6"
    - Topography of the Battle-Field of Cross Keys, VA., 21.36L; Lithograph; 6" x 6"
      by John Pilsen; Julius Bien and Co.
    - Map of Route and Positions First Corps, Army of Virginia, major General Sigel, Commanding from July 7th to Sept. 10th 1862, 21.36M; Lithograph; 6" x 10 1/2"
      by Franz Kappner; Julius Bien and Co.
    - United States Department of the Interior Geological Survey Thorofare gap Quadrangle Virginia, 1943, 21.39; Lithograph; 22 1/2" x 17 3/4"
      by the geological Survey; U.S. Geological Survey
    - U.S. Geological Survey Areal Geology Maryland-Virginia, 1895, 21.40; Lithograph; 17 1/2" x 13 3/4"
    - U.S. Geological Survey Maryland-Virginia, 1914, 21.41; Lithograph; 17 1/2" x 13 3/4"
    - Potomac River (in Four Sheets) Sheet No. 2 from Piney Point to Lower Cedar Point, 1862, 21.45; Hand Colored Lithograph; 23" x 29"
      by A. Maedel, H. S. Barnard and A. Peterson; Survey of the Coast of the United States, Coast Survey Office
    - Second Bull Run Campaign, Situation Night of Aug. 1862, 21.48; Lithograph; 9 1/2" x 12 1/4"
    - Louisa C.H., VA to Hancock, MD; Vicinity of Fredericksburg, 21.49; Hand colored wood engraving; 6 1/2" x 3 3/4"
      by Waters-Son N.Y.
    - Piscataway, MD / Mt. Vernon, VA to Rossburg, MD; Washington, DC, 21.50; Hand colored wood engraving; 7" x 5"
      by G. Woolworth Oolton N.Y.
  - [Maps III] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 31)
    - Pope's Campaign in Virginia, Part of Virginia Showing the Postiions of the Armies on the Morning of August 27, 1862, unnumbered
      by William J. Wilson
    - Capitol Building and Washington, D.C., 5.1; Hand Colored Lithograph; 4 1/4" x 7 1/2"
    - Map of the Peninsular Campaign, 21.51; 7 1/2" x 5 3/4"
      by Fisk and Russell N.Y.
    - Map of Pope's Military Operations in Virginia, August and September 1862, 21.52; Wood Engraving
    - The Battle of Bull Run, Plans of Operations, July 1861, 21.53; Hand Colored Wood Engraving
    - Environs of Warrenton, (Virginia.), undated, 21.55; Wood Engraving
      By Walker & Boutall
  - [Mine Run] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 32)
    - A. Mine Run - Centre of Confederate Position; B. Mine Run - Recrossing at Germania Ford; C. Mine Run - Warren's Last Position, November 1863, 20.37; Hand Colored Wood Engraving
  - [Miscellaneous] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 33)
    - Daily Constitutional Union, July 2, 1864, 20.1
      Newspaper
    - Virginia Troops Crossing the Blue Ridge at Laybreak, an Route for Manassas, Junction, 20.3; Wood Engraving; 7" x 9 1/4"
    - The Civil War in America: Baggage-Wagons and Gun-Carriages of the Army of the Potomac on the Move, April 5, 1862, 20.12; Wood Engraving; 9" x 13 1/2" [Same image as 20.38 in folder 33]
    - The Army of Virginia - Siegel's Corps Being Reviewed by Major-General Pope, August 30, 1862, 20.14A; Wood Engraving; 4 1/2" x 13 3/4"
      by Mr. Anton Kellner; Harper's Weekly
    - The Army of Virginia - Contrabands Coming in to Colonel Cluseret's Head-Quarters, August 30, 1862, 20.14B; Wood Engraving; 4 3/4" x 13 3/4"
      by Mr. Davenport; Harper's Weekly
    - Scene near Trent's House, Formerly General M'Clellan's Head-Quarters - Franklin's Corps Falling Back - June 29, 1862, August 16, 1862, 20.15; Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 13 3/4"
    - Testing the Large Rifled Gun "Union" for the First Time, at Fort Monroe, in the Presence of Generals Wool and Butler, September 9, 1861, 20.18; Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 13 3/4"
      The New-York Illustrated News
    - Sheridan's Campaign - Battle of Winchester - Position of the 19th Corps, Gen. Emery, Sept. 19 - The Centre, October 15, 1864, 20.19A; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 4 3/4" x 14 1/4"
      by J. E. Taylor; Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper
    - Sheridan's Campaign - battle of Winchester - Charge of Crook's 8th Corps - The Right, October 15, 1864, 20.19B; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 4 3/4" x 14 1/4"
    - The March from Williamsburg, May, 1862, 20.20; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 13 3/4"
    - Virginia - The Frightful Disaster at the Pocahontas Coal Mines, March 13th - Scenes at the Mouth of the Mines after the Explosion; A Ghastly Midnight Spectacle - Gathering the Remains of the Victims; A Fruitless Attempt to Enter the Burning Mine, March 22, 1884, 20.21; Wood Engraving; 14 1/2" x 9"
      by J. Lansing and R. P. Johnson; Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper
    - Virginia - The Terrible Disaster at the Pocahontas Coal Mines, March 13th - A Young Wife Discovers the Dead Body of her Husband, Blown from the Mouth of the Mine, March 22, 1884, 20.22; Wood Engraving; 11" x 9"
      by James Lansing; Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper
    - Surrender of Gen. Lee's Army, April 9, 1865; Front View of W. M'Lean's House, at Appomattox Court House, Virginia, in which General Lee Signed the Terms of Surrender; General Lee's Army Firing Its Last Gun; Major Howe's Grave, at the Church near Appomattox Court House; Rear View of Mr. M'Lean's House, Appomattox Court House, November 4, 1865, 20.23; Wood Engraving; 14" x 9 1/4"
      by Col. Battersby; Harper's Weekly
    - From Five Forks to Appomattox - "During the Hours of the Day There Was Constant Pursuit and Fighting.", 20.24; Reproduced Painting; 12" x 19"
      by R. F. Zogbaum; Harper's Weekly
    - Virginia during the War - Scenes in the Army of the Potomac, September and October, 1863. A. Bridge over Cedar Creek; B. Signal Station; C. Frank Leslie in Camp; D. Ruins of Bull Run Bridge; E. A Virginia Hotel; A Virginia Farmer by Day; F. Newsboys Carrying Papers to Camp; G. The Equinoctial Storm, 20.27; Hand Colored Wood Engraving
    - Virginia during the War - Scenes in the Army of the Potomac, September and October, 1863. A. Bridge over Cedar Creek; B. Signal Station; C. Frank Leslie in Camp; D. Ruins of Bull Run Bridge; E. A Virginia Hotel; A Virginia Farmer by Day; F. Newsboys Carrying Papers to Camp; G. The Equinoctial Storm, 20.28A; Hand Colored Wood Engraving
      By Edwin Forbes; The Civil War in the United States [Same image as 20.39 in folder 33]
    - Capture of a Train, near Meadow Bridge, VA., by General Stoneman, 20.28B; Wood Engraving; 3 1/2" x 4 1/2"
    - General Meade Recrossing the Rappahannock, October, 1863, before Lee's Advance, 20.28C; Wood Engraving; 4 3/4" x 14 1/4"
    - Virginia Farmers' Families on Their Way to the Federal Commissary for Provisions, 20.28D; Wood Engraving; 6" x 9 1/4"
    - Defeat of General Braddock, in the French and Indian War, in Virginia, in 1775, 20.30; Hand colored wood engraving; 9 1/2" x 13 1/2"
      Ballou's Pictorial Drawing-Room Companion
    - United States Cavalry Depot, Giesboro, opposite Washington; View of Washington from the Cavalry Depot at Giesboro; Inspection of a New Lot of Horses; Disabled Horses Turned in for Medical Treatment, July 15, 1865, 20.31; Wood engraving; 14" x 20 1/2"
      Harpers Weekly
    - Chronicle of the State of Virginia, June 23, 1855, 20.33; Hand Colored Wood Engraving
      Ballou's Pictorial
    - Return of fifty-seven Wounded Soldiers of the National Army Captured at Bull Run, Scene on Board the United States Steamer "Louisiana", to which they were Transferred, under a Flag of Truce, 20.36; Wood Engraving
    - The Civil War in America: Baggage-Wagons and Gun-Carriages of the Army of the Potomac on the Move, April 5, 1862, 20.38; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9" x 13 1/2"
      The Illustrated London News [Same image as 20.12 in folder 33]
    - Virginia during the War - Scenes in the Army of the Potomac, September and October, 1863. A. Bridge over Cedar Creek; B. Signal Station; C. Frank Leslie in Camp; D. Ruins of Bull Run Bridge; E. A Virginia Hotel; A Virginia Farmer by Day; F. Newsboys Carrying Papers to Camp; G. The Equinoctial Storm, 20.39; Wood Engraving
      By Edwin Forbes; The Civil War in the United States [Same image as 20.28 in folder 33]
  - [Mount Vernon] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 34)
    - Virginia, - Der George Washington Fost No. 103, G. A. R. von New-York schmuckt das Grab Washingtons auf Mount Vernon, am 30. Mai 1881, 16.1; Wood Engraving; 9 1/2" x 14"
  - [Munson's Hill] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 35)
    - A. Franklin's Brigade Passing Arlington Mill on its way to Occupy Munson's Hill; B. A Portion of the Confederate Works on Munson's Hill; C. General McClellan Occupying the Confederate Position at Munson's Hill, October 23, 1861; unnumbered; Wood Engraving
    - A. Munson's Hill as it now Appears with the Fort Erected by the Garibaldi Regiment; B. Photographic Saloon in Camp, Near Ball's Cross Roads, Virginia; C. The Batteries on the Potomac - Budd's Ferry; D. The Batteries on the Potomac - Evansport, November 23, 1861; unnumbered; Wood Engraving
    - Arlington Mills, near the Boundary Line of Munson's Hill, 6.6; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9 1/2" x 13 3/4"
    - The Rebel Fortifications on Munson's Hill, Three Miles Southwest of Arlington Heights, September 21, 1861; 6.9A; Wood Engraving; 7" x 9 1/4"
      Pictorial History of the War of 1861 [same image as 6.17A in folder 35]
    - Skirmishing between the Pickets of the Two Armies, near Munson's Hill - The Hill in the Distance, September 21, 1861; 6.9B; Wood Engraving; 6" x 9 1/4"
      Pictorial History of the War of 1861 [same image as 6.17B in folder 35]
    - The Rebel Fortifications on Munson's Hill, Three Miles Southwest of Arlington Heights, September 21, 1861; 6.17A; Wood Engraving; 7" x 9 1/4"
      Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper [same image as 6.9A in folder 35]
    - Skirmishing between the Pickets of the Two Armies, near Munson's Hill - The Hill in the Distance, September 21, 1861; 6.17B; Wood Engraving; 6" x 9 1/4"
      Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper [same image as 6.9B in folder 35]
    - A Quaker Gun at Munson's Hill and the Works Beyond Embrasured, 20.41; Wood Engraving
  - [Occoquan] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 36)
    - Army Beef Swimming the Occoquan River, Virginia, July 4, 1863, 11.1; Wood Engraving; 4 1/2" x 13 3/4"
    - Bloody Fight at Occoquan, Virginia, February 15, 1862, 11.2; Wood Engraving; 6" x 9"
  - [Potomac] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 37)
    - New Military Road Near the Chain Bridge, Virginia, January 18, 1862, unnumbered; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 13 3/4"
      Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper [same image as 1.12]
    - Views on the Potomac below Washington, May 18, 1861, unnumbered; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 14" x 9"
      The Illustrated London News [same image as 1.6 in folder 37]
    - The Civil War in America: The Great Falls of the Potomac, September 28, 1861, unnumbered; Wood Engraving
    - The War in America: The Chain-Bridge across the Potomac above Georgetown, Looking towards the Virginian Shore, October 12, 1861, unnumbered; Wood Engraving; 7" x 9 1/4"
      The Illustrated London News [same image as 1.3 in folder 37]
    - The Civil War in America: The Long Bridge over the Potomac at Washington, Guarded by United States' Artillery, July 20, 1861, unnumbered; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 7" x 9 1/2"
      The Illustrated London News [same image as 1.1 in folder 37]
    - The Civil War in America: The Long Bridge over the Potomac at Washington, Guarded by United States' Artillery, July 20, 1861, 1.1; Wood Engraving; 7" x 9 1/2"
      The Illustrated London News [same image as unnumbered in folder 37]
    - The Civil War in America: Attack on the Pickets of the Garibaldi Guard on the East Branch of the Potomac, July 20, 1861, 1.2; Wood Engraving; 6 1/2" x 9 1/4" [3 copies]
    - The War in America: The Chain-Bridge across the Potomac above Georgetown, Looking towards the Virginian Shore, October 12, 1861, 1.3; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 7" x 9 1/4"
    - Engagement between the Gunboat Flotilla, Freeborn and Reliance, under the Command of Captain James H. Ward, And a Secession Force at Mathias Point, VA. on the Potomac River - Death of Captain Ward, July 6, 1861, 1.4; Wood Engraving; 9 1/2" x 14"
    - Looking down the Potomac, From the Chain Bridge, 1.5A; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 6 1/2" x 9"
      Picturesque America
    - Arlington Heights, from Grounds in National Observatory, 1.5B; Wood Engraving; 4 1/2" x 6"
    - Views on the Potomac below Washington, May 18, 1861, 1.6; Wood Engraving; 14" x 9"
    - The Campaign in Virginia: General Heintzelman's Division Proceeding down the Potomac, May 3, 1862, 1.7; Wood Engraving; 6 1/4" x 9"
      by E. S. Hall; Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper
    - The Advance Guard of the Grand Army of the United States Crossing the Long Bridge over the Potomac, at 2 A.M. on May 24, 1861, June 8, 1861, 1.9; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9 1/2" x 14"
    - Seine Fishing on the Potomac River, VA., July 24, 1869, 1.10; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 6" x 9 1/4"
      by Wm. L. Sheppard; Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper
    - The Confederates Crossing the Potomac, September, 1862, 1.11A; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 13 3/4"
    - Monument on the Battle-Field of Bull Run September, 1862, 1.11B; Wood Engraving; 6" x 7"
    - New Military Road Near the Chain Bridge, Virginia, January 18, 1862, 1.12; Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 13 3/4"
      Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper [2 copies]
    - Federal Battery at Chain Bridge - Exercise with the Big Guns, September 23, 1861, 1.13; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 7 1/2" x 20"
      The New York Illustrated News
    - Falls of the Potomac, from the Maryland Shore, May 6, 1882, 1.14; Hand colored wood engraving; 9 1/2" x 14"
      by A. R. Waud; Pictorial War Record
    - North Battery of the Confederates at Shipping Point, on the Virginia Side of the Potomac, Looking up the River, 1.15; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9" x 14"
    - The Civil War in America: Cutting off a Confederate Despatch-Galley on the Potomac near Freestone Point, November 9, 1861; 1.15; Wood Engraving
    - The Rebel Batteries on the Potomac now in Prossession of our Troops, March 22, 1862, 1.16; Wood Engraving
    - The "Hotel" at Centerville, Virginia, September 7, 1861, 7.1A; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 4" x 4 1/2"
    - Ruins of the Bridge across the Potomac at Berlin, September 7, 1861, 7.1B; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 4" x 4 1/2"
    - The Loudon heights across the Potomac, opposite the Position Lately Occupied by General Banks - Harper's Ferry in the Distance, September 7, 1861, 7.1C; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 5 1/4" x 9"
    - Grand Review of General McDowell's Corps D'Armee, by Secretary Cameron, on the South Side of the Potomac, June 17, 1861, 20.40; Wood Engraving
  - [Potomac II] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 38)
    - The Potomac Blockade at Quantico Creek. - Parrot Guns Shelling the Confederate Steamer "George Page." Confederate Batteries in the Distance Firing on Passing Schooners, 1.21; Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 20 1/4"
      by A. R. Waud; The Pictorial Battles of the Civil War
  - [Quantico] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 39)
    - Johnson's Map of the Vicinity of Richmond and Peninsular Campaign in Virginia: Showing also the Interesting Localities along the James, Chickahominy and York Rivers, 21.22; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 17 1/2" x 26 3/4"
      by Johnson and Ward
    - General Topographical Map [Virginia to Maryland], 21.25; Lithograph; 16" x 27"
    - Johnson's Virginia, Delaware, Maryland and West Virginia, 21.26; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 16 3/4" x 23 1/4"
    - No. 1 Map, from Maj. A.H. Campbell's Surveys, Showing the Positions of the Camps and Pickets of the 2d Corps, A. N. VA., May 3d, 1864, and the Routes of March from May 4th to May 21st, 1864, to the Battles of the Wilderness and Spotsylvania C. H., VA., 21.30A; Lithograph; 7 1/2" x 11"
    - No. 5 Map, from Maj. A.H. Campbell's Surveys, Showing the Routes and Positions of the 2d Coprs, A. N. VA., from May 21st to May 27th, 1864, 21.30B; Lithograph; 11" x 8"
    - No. 7 Map, from Maj. A.H. Campbell's Surveys, Showing the Routes, Camps,and Positions of the 2d Corps, A. N. VA., from May 27th to June 13th, 1864, 21.30C; Lithograph; 10 1/2" x 8 1/4"
    - No. 11 Map, Showing Routes and Camps of the Army of the Valley Dist. from Staunton, VA., to Washington, D.C., and back to Strasburg, VA., from June 27th to July 22d, 1864, 21.30D; Lithograph; 8 3/4" x 14"
    - No. 99 Wickham's Attack on Fed. Cav., Nov. 22d, 1864, 21.30E; Lithograph; 3" x 2 3/4"
    - No. 8 Map Showing the Routes and Camps of the 2d Corps, A.N.V., from Gaines' Mill to Lynchburg, VA., June 13th to 18th, 1864, and of the Army of the Valley District from Lynchburg to Salem and Staunton, VA., June 19th to 27th, 1864, 21.30F; Lithograph; 5 1/4" x 12 1/2"
    - No. 6 Map, from Maj. A.H. Campbell's Surveys, Showing Position of 2d Corps, A. N. VA., at Hanover Junction, VA. May 22d to May 27th, 1864, 21.30G; Lithograph; 5 3/4" x 8"
    - Map of Battle-Grounds of August 28th, 29th, and Vath, 1862 in the Vicinity VA Groveton, Prince William Co., VA., 21.42; Lithograph; 22 1/4" x 26 1/2"
      Engineer Department. U.S. Army
    - Map of Battle-Grounds of August 28th, 29th, and 30th, 1862 in the Vicinity of Groveton, Prince William Co., VA., 21.43; Lithograph; 22 1/4" x 26 1/2"
  - [Rapidan] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 40)
    - The War in America: Winter Quarters of the Left Wing of the Confederate Army on the Rapidan, April 2, 1864, 20.16; Wood Engraving; 6 1/2" x 9 1/2"
  - [Rappahannock River] (Oversize MC Cage, Folder 41)
    - A. General Pope's Head-Quarters at Rappahannock Station - General Sigel on the Roof Watching the Enemy; B. Skirmish at Freeman's Ford, August 27 - Death by General Bohlen; C. Warrenton, Virginia, Lately Occupied by the Army of Virginia, September 13, 1852, unnumbered; Wood Engraving
    - Shelling the Rebel Rifle-Pits on the Rappahannock Previous to Sedgwick's Crossing, June 27, 1863, 14.2; Hand Colored Wood Engraving; 9 1/4" x 13 3/4"
    - Building Pontoons on the Rappahannock, May 16, 1863, 14.3; Wood Engraving; 11" x 9 1/4"
      Harper's Weekly [2 copies]
    - Die Pontons auf dem Wege nach dem Rappahannock, 14.4; Wood Engraving; 9 1/2" x 8 3/4"